As a career oriented person, Ryan has his craft and expertise to the whole cycle of Recruitment, Employee Relations, and **Labor Relations.** His specialization for sourcing had led tremendous remarks for the Talent Acquisitions and through his extensive experience in holding NLRC cases, his skills for Employee and Labor Relations exists. In his present atmosphere, he overviews the whole On-boarding, process of Sourcing, Recruitment, Employee relations to his candidates and employees situated in California, USA and South East ASia

Apart for being an HR practitioner, he also deals with academe as a part-time professor, Researcher, and Department Head of Don Bosco Global College to which he teaches and oversees Psychology as a course.

EDUCATIONAL INFORMATION:

Doctor of Naturopathic Medicine Major in Family Medicine

International Medical School of Integrative Medicine 2018- present

Master of Science in Psychology

Laguna College of Business & Arts 2011- 2013

Bachelor of Science in Psychology

University of Cabuyao (Formerly Pamantasan ng Cabuyao) 2007-2011

*Academic Distinction

English Proficiency NC II- TESDA

April 2009- May 2009 *Outstanding Trainee

AWARDS AND CITATIONS:

Outstanding Professor 2012-2013

Second and Third Trimester
Don Bosco Institute of Arts and Sciences

Academic Distinction

Pamantasan ng Cabuyao

Business Manager 2009-2010

Pamantasan ng Cabuyao

Scholar- Gov. Teresita Lazaro

2008-2010

President

Youth Circle- Cabuyao City, Laguna 2007-2010



Ryan Jay M. Lacuña

Unit 21i Pioneer Woodland Condominium, Mandaluyong City 0935-246-0421 Ryan.donboscocabuyao@amail.com



TEACHING EXPERIENCES:

Professor

Don Bosco Global College 2015- present

Psychology Associate Professor Laguna State Polytechnic University 2013- 2015

CORPORATE EXPERIENCES:

Recruitment Lead

-August 2018- present

Registry Ally, Torrance, CA, USA

- *Full cycle recruitment of Healthcare professional in USA
- *Manage 5 recruiters for their recruitment activities.

ASEAN Sourcing Consultant

-January 2018- January 2019

Novartis Through Korn Ferry, Petaling Jaya, Malaysia

- *Head hunting of Pharma professional in Malaysia & Singapore
- *Manage sourcing strategies for both countries

US TALENT ACQUISITION

-May 2015- August 2017

Platinum BPO Consulting, Ortigas Center, Pasig City

- *Head hunting of healthcare professionals in California, USA
- *Manage end-to-end recruitment up to processing of HMO, taxes, On-boarding, training, employment contract & termination

US RECRUITMENT SPECIALIST

-January 2015- May 2015

UNI Healthcare Staffing, Ortigas Center, Pasig City

- *Head hunting of healthcare professionals in California, USA
- *Manage end-to-end recruitment from on-boarding to contract termination

HR OPERATIONS SUPPORT SERVICES

-March 2014- January 2015

TotalDev Multi-Purpose Cooperative, Mandaluyong City

- *Manager of Recruitment, ER, Training, and Labor Relations
- *Oversees the relationship with the client through providing excellent outsourced HR services

HR & GUIDANCE HEAD

-May 2012- February 2014

Don Bosco Global College, Cabuyao City, Laguna

- *Oversees the HR Department and the Guidance Office
- *Manage Recruitment, ER, Training, and Labor Relations, Compensation & Benefits
- *Provided excellent services to college staffs and students

HR OFFICER (Recruitment & ER)

-April 2011-April 2012

Mark Enterprises Inc., Cabuyao City, Laguna

- *Oversees the Recruitment and ER processes
- *Provided excellent services to clients as outsourced HR